badwarebusters.org 2009-11-24

# Privacy Policy - BadwareBusters

**BadwareBusters.org Privacy Statement**

**Summary**

BadwareBusters.org is operated by StopBadware.org, a not-for-profit, public interest research and education initiative of the Berkman Center for Internet & Society at Harvard University, based in Cambridge, MA, USA. The StopBadware.org project and its researchers are conducting academic research and public education to address problems raised by potentially harmful software, and seeking innovative community-driven solutions. As part of this project, users can submit information to this website, BadwareBusters.org. Some additional information is automatically collected when you visit the site. We use this information for research, and we may share some of this information with other researchers.

We are committed to respecting and protecting your personal privacy. This Privacy Statement describes what information the site collects, how this information is used, and with whom we may share the information. Your submission of data to the site indicates your agreement with the terms of the Privacy Statement. Because this statement may change, please check back for updates to this Privacy Statement.

Here is a summary of key information you can read in more detail below:

  * Information you post to public areas of the site is public. Please keep this in mind when choosing how much personally identifying information to share.

  * Personally identifying information you share with BadwareBusters.org privately, such as your email address, will never be shared with any outside entity without your explicit consent.

  * We may share aggregated information about users of our site with other researchers or the public, but this will never include any personally identifying information.

  * Some information about your computer and network connection is collected automatically by the website and the analytics tools we use to help us understand our website traffic. We will not use this information to track your individual use of the site or share personally identifying information that has been collected automatically, except in cases of violations of our Terms of Service or if required by law enforcement.

  * You will only receive emails from BadwareBusters.org that you have opted in to receive, apart from occasional necessary communications regarding your account.

  * We will do our best to protect your information, within the requirements of complying with requests from law enforcement.

If you choose to create a user account on BadwareBusters.org, you will also be able to use that account wherever a user account is necessary at StopBadware.org. Your use of StopBadware.org and any personally identifying information you may submit there are governed by the [StopBadware.org privacy policy](http://www.stopbadware.org/home/privacy).

If you have any questions or concerns about this policy, please contact us at contact@badwarebusters.org.

* * *

**Publicly Submitted Information**

If you elect to sign up for and participate in the BadwareBusters.org community, any content you contribute or other information you submit to public areas of the site may be publicly displayed, including personally identifying information. This includes information you include in your public user profile, and information you include in messages posted to the community forums. Your user name is displayed to viewers of BadwareBusters.org along with messages or other information that you publicly submit. Much of the content available on BadwareBusters.org is created by users of the site, and not by BadwareBusters.org, StopBadware.org, or their staff and affiliates.

Should you include additional personally identifying information in messages you post to BadwareBusters.org, your user profile, or other parts of the site, please note that this information will be publicly viewable. We are not asking you for personally identifying information and we strongly encourage you not to include such information in your posts to BadwareBusters.org, except for the minimum amount necessary to make use of the help available from the BadwareBusters.org community. For example, if your website has been hacked, you may want to share your website’s URL, but should not need to share additional personal information such as your phone number or email address.

The information that you submit may be used by us for research purposes. We may share information other than your e-mail address with third parties who are engaged in research or analysis that we believe in good faith is legitimate. For instance, we intend to make some version of the aggregate data we gather available generally to individuals and organizations who are also working to put an end to badware, which may include other academic researchers, policy-makers, and companies. We also may make aggregate data that does not include personally identifying information available generally to the public.

**Your Email Address**

If you choose to sign up for a BadwareBusters.org account, you will need to provide an email address as part of the registration process. That email address will be used for the purposes of account registration verification, as well as any occasional necessary communications directly related to the logistics of your account. If you elect to sign up for additional opt-in emails from BadwareBusters.org, such as newsletters or emailed alerts about activity on the site, we will use your email address only for the purpose of sending you those additional messages for which you have opted in. We will not share your email address with any other parties without your consent.

**Information the Site Automatically Collects**

Whether or not you submit information to BadwareBusters.org, the site logs the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using when you visit the site, the browser version that you are using to access the site, and the operating system installed and running on the computer that you are using.

We also may use these logs to compile aggregate data for research purposes. We may share data from these logs with third parties who are engaged in research that we believe in good faith is legitimate and who agree to use the information for research purposes only. This information will be studied and/or shared only in aggregate, and never in connection with your personally identifying information.

While it is our standard policy not to use IP address logs to track the sessions of individual users, there are some important exceptions. These exceptions are in cases of reported violations of our Terms of Service [LINK], and in cases where we are required to so by law enforcement (see “Disclosure of Information to Law Enforcement” below).

**Google Analytics**

We make some of the information the site automatically collects available to Google Inc. for the purpose of using Google Analytics, a service that helps us to better understand how our visitors use BadwareBusters.org and how the site can be improved. This information may include IP addresses, browser versions used by visitors, the pages visited on the site, and other information. This data is analyzed in the aggregate, and individuals are not tracked. No personally identifying information will be submitted to Google for the purposes of the Google Analytics service, and Google Analytics is governed by [Google, Inc.’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy.html). We also reserve the right to use additional website analytics services provided by vendors in addition to Google, Inc. in the future, so please check back for updates to this section.

**Commercial Use of Personal Information**

We will never rent or sell your information to anyone. We will not share your name or e-mail address with third parties except with your consent, and only on the condition that the third parties agree not to use your name or e-mail for commercial purposes.

**Disclosure of Information to Law Enforcement**

If we receive a warrant or subpoena for user information, we may disclose requested records to law enforcement authorities or outside parties seeking information through the legal process. In the event that we are required by law (including a court order) to disclose the information you submit and we have your contact information, we will provide you with notice (unless we are prohibited) that a request for your information has been made so that you may object to the disclosure. We will send this notice by e-mail to the address you have given us. We prefer to independently object to over-broad requests for access to information about users of the site, but we cannot assure you that we will be able to do this in all cases. If you do not challenge the disclosure request yourself, we may be legally required to turn over your information.

**Jurisdiction**

BadwareBusters.org is based in the United States, and the servers and data processors used to maintain this site are located in the U.S. Please note that any personally identifiable information we obtain about you will be stored under U.S. privacy standards and regulations.

**Cookies**

BadwareBusters.org uses session cookies that record the IP address, browser and operating system of computers used to access the site, as well as information about navigation through pages of the site. Session cookies are temporary files that are erased when you close all browser windows. The cookies are in place to help the site work properly and to improve the user experience and will not be used to track your individual use of the site.

**Links to Independent Websites**

Pages hosted by the site may link to independently-run web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such web sites.

**Children’s Privacy**

You must be at least 13 years of age to submit information to BadwareBusters.org. The site is intended for adults and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years old. If you are a parent or legal guardian of a child under age 13 who you believe has submitted personal information to the site, please contact us immediately at contact@stopbadware.org.

**Changes to the Privacy Statement**

We retain the right to make changes, in our sole discretion, to this Privacy Statement. Any changes will be reflected in the Privacy Statement when the changes take effect. The privacy policies that apply to any information you submit will be those contained in the Privacy Statement that is in effect and posted on the site at the time that you submit the information. Please review the Privacy Statement each time you use the site.

**Effective Date**

This Privacy Statement is effective as of October 30, 2008

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, you may contact us by email at contact@badwarebusters.org or by mail to:

StopBadware.org  
Berkman Center for Internet & Society  
Harvard Law School  
23 Everett Street, 2nd Floor  
Cambridge, MA 02138
